


                     ╔══════════════════════════╗
                     ║                          ║
                     ║       RosettaShard       ║
                     ║       version .8.5       ║
                     ║         05-08-07         ║
                     ╚══════════════════════════╝

         ┌─────────────┐
         │Installation:│
         └─────────────┘
            Just copy the directory RosettaShard to your PSP's GAME directory.
            If you have a previous version of RosettaShard installed, please
            delete the contents of the installation folder in the game directory
            on your PSP. Be sure to leave your Languages folder in tact. Do not
            delete the Language folder unless you intend to replace it with a
            new copy.

            This version of RosettaShard comes preloaded with 8 sample cards
            to give you an idea of what the application can do.

            This application is compatible with the Rosetta Stone language sets
            without any conversion needed. Unfortunately it seems some of the
            audio files from Rosetta Stone are not perfect. They play fine on
            the PC, but the PSP audio libraries are not able to play some
            without distortion. Copy your Language Set lessons to the Language
            directory in the RosettaShard installation folder. If your Language
            Set has much distortion, it will need to be repaired. This will be
            done with a PC application which will be released as soon as it is
            completed. Until then, you can repair them yourself by the following:

                Rename the files so the extension SWA becomes MP3.
                Encode the files to MP3 at 22khz with a bitrate of 80kbits.
                Rename the files so the extension MP3 becomes SWA.

            Some files in some Language Sets are in format SND. I have not yet
            managed to include support for these but I will continue to try to
            do so. For now, Encode the files to MP3 at 44khz with a bitrate of
            128kbits. Leave the extension as MP3. If you want them at 22khz so
            you can save a little disk space, encode them at 22khz and rename
            to SWA.

         ┌─────────┐
         │Controls:│
         └─────────┘
            The controls for RosettaShard are as simple as I could make them.
            By pressing Start or Select you can get to the Options Menu, from
            there you can go to Controls and see animated descriptions of four
            different control schemes. The fourth one "Select Method" has not
            yet been implemented, but the others are finished.

              In the menu: 
                Everything behaves as normal. Up, Down, Left, Right to move
                or change values. Cross to choose an item, Circle to go back  
                to the previous menu. Home button to quit.

              In the lesson default controls ("Classic Controls"):
                ┌─────────────────────────┐
                │┌─────┐┌─────┐    phrase │
                ││  1  ││  2  │           │
                ││     ││     │           │
                │└─────┘└─────┘           │
                │┌─────┐┌─────┐           │
                ││  3  ││  4  │           │
                ││     ││     │     score │
                │└─────┘└─────┘           │
                └─────────────────────────┘

                To select card 1           : Press UP  
                To select card 2           : Press TRIANGLE
                To select card 3           : Press DOWN
                To select card 4           : Press CROSS

                To replay the audio        : Press SQUARE
                To replay the audio slower : Press CIRCLE

         ┌───────────┐
         │Changelog: │ 
         └───────────┘
            The HOME button is fixed. It now brings up the HOME screen and
            works as normal.
                                                                            
            In Choose Setup -> Available Card Sets: Only Units and Lessons
            which are present on the memory stick are available to select.
                                                                        
            In Choose Setup -> Available Card Sets: Lesson Descriptions have   
            been removed as they were not exceedingly useful. In fact the
            whole menu system has been replaced.

            Skins have been removed for now. This will be a feature in a
            later version. Currently the Skin can only be changed by replacing
            the images themselves. The entire interface can be skinned this way.
            
         ┌───────────┐
         │Dumb Bugs: │ 
         └───────────┘
            I forgot to correct a code swap I made at the last minute.
            When a phrase is first spoken and displayed on screen it is yellow.
            Once you have selected your answer the text becomes black until
            the next phrase is posed. Sorry about that. This will be fixed in
            version .9 which will be out this week. (Today being May 8th)

         ┌────────────┐
         │For Updates:│
         └────────────┘
            At the time of this writing, the most recent version   
            can be downloaded from http://www.psp-hacks.com/file/1114
            